foreign
let's let T sub K represent the sum of
the first K positive integers the sum
can be represented by a triangular array
of Cubes like the one pictured here
where there's K cubes in the bottom row
and one cube in the top row
so let's consider T sub n plus 1 which
can be represented by a triangular array
of cubes with n plus 1 cubes on the
bottom
now construct n different copies of this
triangular array and place them side by
side like this this staircase diagram
contains a total of n times T sub n plus
1 with cubes
let's remove the N by n plus 1 rectangle
in the back of this staircase this
rectangle can be decomposed into two
triangular arrays each of these
triangular arrays has n cubes in the
bottom so represents the number T sub n
we can take these two arrays and place
them on either side of the remaining
staircase we see that the staircase
diagram now has a total of n plus two
copies of the Triangular array
representing the number T sub n
therefore the total number of Cubes is n
plus 2 times T sub n but we can use this
formula to see that t sub n plus 1 is
equal to n plus 2 over n multiplied by T
sub n the numbers given by T sub K are
called the Triangular numbers so this is
a recurrence for the Triangular numbers